DAN KLEIN: We're going to talk a
little about one more class of
algorithms for improving structure.
This is a more advanced algorithm, and
I'm not going to go through all of the
details and conditions.
But I want to give you a sense that
there are other approaches then
deleting nodes that let you take a
complex graph structure that's not a
tree, and apply a tree structured
algorithm to it.
The idea here is you look at your
constraint satisfaction problem, and
you think, well, actually, it's a
bunch of small problems glued
together, right?
You can think of each constraint,
really, as a small problem.
If these problems were separate, they
wouldn't be so hard to solve.
And so there's a kind of divide and
conquer way of using the tree
structure algorithm that's
really neat.
So what we do is we create
mega variables.
Each mega variable is going to be a
sub part of the original problem.
And then we're going to glue the mega
variables up together in a way that
will have this meta graph, and in the
meta CSP we will have tree structure.
So for example, we could take this
little sub part of this CSP about WA,
NT, and SA, and it says they
all have to be different.
Well, this is part of the CSP.
You have to solve this
to solve the CSP.
By itself, it's not so hard
because it's small.
But you know, also NT, Q, and
SA all have to be different.
And that's another small problem.
And to solve the whole thing,
you have to solve this.
But again, it's really small.
And so we can do this.
We can write down all of the sub
problems, and we can recognize that
we're going to have to solve them all.
So for each of these sub problems, we
can say, actually, you're just kind of
a mega variable in a meta problem.
So here's mega variable one.
It represents this whole sub problem,
and the values it can take on are
joint assignments to those
three variables.
So a valid value for mega variable
one is RGB for WA, SA, and NT.
And then we just list
all the valid ones.
And there aren't too many variables
in mega variable one, so
this isn't too hard.
We're essentially listing all the
solutions to the sub problem.
And then mega variable two,
it's got solutions.
We can list them.
And aren't that many because
it's not that big.
And then we can continue doing
this for all of them.
Now, this isn't quite enough, because if
we solved all of these problems, it
would be easy.
But then we might find that in mega
variable one, the Northern Territory
is green, but in mega variable two,
the Northern Territory is blue.
So somehow we have to solve all the
problems, and that's just unary
constraints here.
But we also have to make sure that
everything is consistent.
And so we have constraints between the
variables that say that where they
share variables, they have to
agree in the assignment.
So for example, we might say that for M1
and M2 to agree, here's the list of
valid options, right?
And in particular, NT has to either
be green in both, or red in
both, or blue in both.
So here is a kind of meta CSP that
encodes the original one, and can be
solved using tree structured
approaches.
But of course, the domains
are now much bigger.
And there's one other tricky thing here
that I haven't really given you
the details of, which is you have to
make sure that they overlap in just
the right way to guarantee
consistency.
At just the right way, it's something
called the running
intersection property.
And we won't talk about the running
intersection property more here, but
you can kind of imagine what
it must look like.
It must be the things overlaps
sufficiently that you can't have the
Northern Territory in two
places without appearing
everywhere in between.